Leon Morten Richter

BACKEND DEVELOPER · AUTOMATION ENGINEER

Sophienhof 17, 24256 Fargau-Pratjau

□ (+49) 15224581631 | ■ leonrichter@fastmail.com | ★ www.leonmortenrichter.de | ☑ M0r13n

Summary.

Currently I am working at Raytheon Anschütz GmbH. There, I support the QM team by writing system tests for embedded naval navigation systems. I have made a significant contribution to test automation in the products Radar NX, WECDIS NX and SYNAPSIS. In my spare time I support the local startup Smartphoniker. Here I solved my first small programming tasks. Over the time we developed a lot of different tools, websites and services. Due to the fact that I am the only developer there, I could gain experience in the whole technology stack.

Education

CAU(Chrisitian-Albrechts-University)

Kiel, Germany

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ECONOMICS

Aug. 2016 - Sep. 2020

Skills___

DevOps Docker, Jenkins, TravisCl, GitHub Actions, Git, JIRA

Backend Flask, Django, Wordpress, NodeJS, Spring

Databases Postgres, MySQL, Redis, Elastic

Frontend HTML, CSS, Hugo

System Administration Windows, MacOS, Linux, Bash, Powershell

Programming languages Python, Javascript, Java, C, SQL, Autohotkey, LaTeX

Languages German, English

Work Experience_

Raytheon Anschütz GmbH

Kiel, Germany

WORKING STUDENT: TEST AUTOMATION

Jun. 2019 - Sep. 2020

- Further development and maintenance of an existing test framework based on Autohotkey for the automatic execution of system tests.
- Development of an internal web application for the decentralized administration of test systems. This included a web application together with Raspberry PI based consoles.
- A Python-based application for the automated dashboard creation for JIRA.
- Smaller scripts based on Python.

Smartphoniker GmbH

Kiel, Germany since Jun.2017

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Designed and deployed a strongly micro service-oriented company infrastructure.

- Provisioned fully automated CI/CD pipelines based on GitHub Actions, TravisCI, Scalingo and Docker.
- Implemented a whole merchandise management system used by over 20 employees. Mainly based on Flask, Postgres, Redis, Celery.
- Deployed an online shop. Based on Flask and Postgres.
- · Maintained an existing Wordpress website.
- Designed a custom Kiosk to display ads and information as part of a digital signage campaign. This included the creation of custom images for Raspberry PI's
- · Integrated existing services (Vigil, Raidr) into existing infrastructure and published actively maintained libraries for them on PyPi.
- I took care of the hosting and administration of our servers
- I was responsible for the constant availability, reliability, correctness and security of our systems which have led to over 100,000 successful repairs
- Many more things like bots for Slack, monitoring systems or status pages

Extracurricular Activity _____

Maintenance of several open source packages avaible on PyPi

MAINTAINER

- pyais
- · py-vigil-reporter
- py-raider-reporter

Stanford's CS116 - From Nand to Tetris I

STUDENT since Oct. 2019

- Building a Modern Computer From First Principles
- Boolean logic and arithmetic. Sequential logic.
- Machine language.
- Computer architecture.
- Assembler and program control.
- High-Level language and Compilers.

Harvard - CS50

Student Sep. 2019 - Oct. 2019

- Introduction to Computer Science.
- Solved different tasks using C, Python and Javascript.
- Deepend my knowlegde about basic algorithms and math.